Guide to the Henrietta C. Bartlett Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Henrietta C. Bartlett papers
1471-1961
GEN MSS 336
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
7.1
(17 boxes and 1 portfolio)
Collection includes letters to Bartlett from various correspondents, concerned mainly with bibliographical matters, relating especially to Shakespeare and his period. Correspondents include Joseph Quincy Adams, Tucker Brooke, Beverly Chew, George Watson Cole, Harvey Cushing, John Drinkwater, John Farquhar Fulton, W. W. Greg, Geoffrey Keynes, Amy Lowell, Ronald Brunlees McKerrow, Julia Marlowe, William Allan Neilson, Alfred Edward Newton, Alfred William Pollard, Seymour de Ricci, Otis Skinner, Edward Hugh Sothern, Chauncey Brewster Tinker, John Dover Wilson, and the Henry E. Huntington Library. The Papers also include lecture notes on bibliographical subjects; sample pages of early books ca. 1471-1675; six boxes of 4 x 5 glass slides used in her lectures; minutes, membership lists and printed material from the Hroswitha Club in New York; and notes and newspaper clippings related to various authors, libraries, and book collecting.
Bartlett, Henrietta C. (Henrietta Collins), 1873-1963
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The Henrietta C. Bartlett Papers were donated to the library by Henrietta C. Bartlett between 1941-1954.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Restricted Fragile Papers in Box 17 may only be consulted with permission of the appropriate curator. Preservation photocopies for reference use have been substituted in the main files.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Henrietta C. Bartlett, born in 1873, was a long-time resident of New Haven. Her father, Charles G. Bartlett, received his M.A. from Yale in 1888, and at least one of her brothers attended Yale as an undergraduate. Bartlett herself was involved with the University as an active donor to the library, with gifts ranging from her extensive library of rare books to her own personal papers. Bartlett gave many lectures at Yale during the 1920's and 1930's on the subjects of bibliography, collecting, and rare books, and taught private pupils for many years, as well. Her work in bibliography centered around the works of William Shakespeare, and include Mr. William Shakespeare, Original and Early Editions of his Quartos and Folios (1923), and Census of Shakespeare's Plays in Quarto, 1594-1709 (1916 and 1939, with Alfred W. Pollard), both printed by the Yale University Press, under the auspices of the Elizabethan Club. She also published a volume of poetry, Verses, 1888-1912, in 1949. She died in 1963.
Scope and Contents
The Henrietta C. Bartlett Papers contain correspondence, research files and other materials related to Bartlett's research, publications and lectures on bibliography and collecting, generally concerned with Shakespeare and other writers of his time. The Papers are organized into four series. Series I, Correspondence, consists primarily of letters to Bartlett, and some third-party letters. Where copies or originals of letters from Bartlett are included, a note has been made in the box and folder list. Series II, Writings, contains typescripts and sample pages of writings by Bartlett, typescript lectures, notes, pages from early printed books, glass slides, and other materials related to her lectures. Series III, Research Files, contains newspaper clippings, notes and articles on authors, book collectors, and libraries, specimen pages from various printers, and miscellaneous printed items. Series IV, Hroswitha Club, consists of club minutes, membership lists, printed items and other material related to the Hroswitha Club, a group of women interested in book and manuscript collecting. Restricted Fragile Papers contains material from Series II and III. Oversize contains material from Series II.
Bibliography -- English literature; Book collecting; Collectors and collecting; Printing -- Specimens; Women teachers; Women -- Education; Slides (photographs); Adams, Joseph Quincy, 1881-1946; Bartlett, Henrietta C. (Henrietta Collins), 1873-1963; Brooke, Tucker, 1883-1946; Chew, Beverly, 1850-1924; Cole, George Watson, 1850-1939; Cushing, Harvey, 1869-1939; Drinkwater, John, 1882-1937; Fulton, John F. (John Farquhar), 1899-1960; Greg, W. W. (Walter Wilson), 1875-1959; Keynes, Geoffrey, 1887-1982; Lowell, Amy, 1874-1925; Marlowe, Julia, 1865-1950; McKerrow, R. B. (Ronald Brunlees), 1872-1940; Neilson, William Allan, 1869-1946; Newton, A. Edward (Alfred Edward), 1864-1940; Pollard, Alfred W. (Alfred William), 1859-1944; Ricci, Seymour de, 1881-1942; Shakespeare, William, 1564-1616 ( Bibliography); Skinner, Otis, 1858-1942; Sothern, E. H. (Edward Hugh), 1859-1933; Tinker, Chauncey Brewster, 1876-1963; Wilson, John Dover, 1881-1969; Henry E. Huntington Library and Art Gallery; Hroswitha Club
- Correspondence, 1905-1960, n.d.; Series I; 2.1' (5 boxes)
  - LETTERS TO HENRIETTA C. BARTLETT
    - Abel, Walter, 1937, [1940?] (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Adams, Joseph Quincy, 1922-36 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Adler, E. N., n.d. (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Adler, Elmer, 1930, 1932 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Aldenham, Alban George Henry Gibbs, [1921], 1926 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Allen, Helen Mary, 1929 May 30 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Allen, P. S. (Percy Stafford), 1920-27 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - American Art Association
      Related Archival Materials note
      See: Anderson Galleries, Box 1, folder 8
    - Anderson Galleries, 1915-29 (Box 1, Folder 8)
      Scope and Contents
      Includes: Letters from American Art Association
      Includes: Letters from Mitchell Kennerley
      Includes: Letters from Arthur Swann
    - "B" General, 1919-29 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Babb, James T.
      See: Yale University Library, Box 5, folders 273-278
    - Bakeless, John Edwin, 1933-40 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Baker, Ernest Albert
      See: University of London, School of Librarianship, Box 5, folder 252
    - Bamford, M. [secretary to Sir Alfred Law], 1936 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Barnett, Crawford, 1960 Feb 21 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Bartlett, Harry, 1917-18 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Baugh, Albert Croll, 1928 Feb 25 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Beatty, Alfred Chester, 1927 Jun 20 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Bell, Eric S., 1935-46, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Bellinger, Alfred Raymond
      See: The Elizabethan Club, Box 1, folder 64
    - Bemis, Frank B., 1932 Feb 23 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Bennett, H. S. (Henry Stanley), 1946 Apr 25 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Bernard Quaritch, Ltd., 1914-60 (Box 1, Folder 19)
      Includes: Letters from F. S. Ferguson, and copy of reply from HCB
    - Berry, W. Turner, 1929 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Bibliothèque Nationale (France), 1946 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Birmingham Public Libraries, 1937-46 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Bishop, Cortlandt F. (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Black, Matthew Wilson, 1946-54, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 24)
      See also: Series III, Research Files, Notes on Shakespeare Editions, Box 13, folder 369
    - Brick Row Book Shop, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 25)
      Includes: Letters from Edmond Byrne Hackett
    - British Museum, Department of Printed Books, 1927-46 (Box 1, Folder 26)
      Includes: Carbon of letter from HCB to W. A. Marsden, one letter from Marsden to Sotheby & Co., and their reply
      Includes: Letter from R. Farquharson Stuart
    - Broadbent, Henry, 1922-23 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Brooke, Tucker, 1920-[39?] (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Brown University Library, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Bull, Ludlow Seguine, 1949 Sep 24 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Bulman, Emmeline, 1939-41 (Box 1, Folder 31-32)
    - Byrne, M. St. Clare, 1941 Jul 3 (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - "C" General, 1914-45, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - C. A. Stonehill, Inc., 1946-54 (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - Cameron, Kenneth Walter, 1931 (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - Canby, Henry Seidel, 1922 (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - Cardiff (Wales) Public Libraries, 1918-46 (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - Carl H. Pforzheimer Library, 1922-56, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 39)
      Includes: Letters from Emma Unger
      Includes: Letters from Carl Howard Pforzheimer
    - Chapman, R. W. (Robert William), 1929, 1934 (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - Chew, Beverley, 1910-22 (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - Chew, Thomas H., 1924, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 42)
    - Chrystal, Sir George William, 1934 Dec 26 (Box 1, Folder 43)
    - Clark, Kenneth Willis, 1932 Nov 2 (Box 1, Folder 44)
    - Clawson, John L., 1923 Nov 22 (Box 1, Folder 45)
    - Clay, Charles Travis, 1934 Jun 12 (Box 1, Folder 46)
    - Cohen, William W., 1937 Oct 19 (Box 1, Folder 47)
    - Cole, George Watson
      See: Henry E. Huntington Library, Box 2, folders 100-102
    - Collamore, H. B., 1941 Apr 16 (Box 1, Folder 48)
    - Columbia University, School of Library Service, 1931 Oct 23 (Box 1, Folder 49)
    - Cost, Sue M., 1946 (Box 1, Folder 50)
      Regarding the collection of Alfred Sutro
    - Craigie, William A., 1923 Jun 14 (Box 1, Folder 51)
    - Craster, Herbert Henry Edmund, 1915 Mar 25 (Box 1, Folder 52)
    - Cushing, Harvey, 1931, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 53)
      Includes: Carbon of letter from HCB
    - Day, George Parmly, 1922-1925 (Box 1, Folder 54)
    - De Vinne, Theodore Low, 1905 Dec 20 (Box 1, Folder 55)
    - Dickson, William Kirk, 1929 (Box 1, Folder 56)
    - Dixon, Emma, 1939 Jun (Box 1, Folder 57)
    - Dodd, Robert H., 1932 Mar 25 (Box 1, Folder 58)
    - Donaldson, Norman Vaux
      See: Yale University Press, Box 5, folders 273-278
    - Dowling, S. R., 1937-38 (Box 1, Folder 59)
      Regarding the Crichton-Stuart collection of Shakespeariana
    - Drake, James F., 1924, 1928 (Box 1, Folder 60)
    - Drake, James H., 1938, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 61)
    - Drinkwater, John, 1922-25 (Box 1, Folder 62)
    - Dunn, Esther Cloudman, 1937 Oct 18 (Box 1, Folder 63)
      Includes: Carbon of reply from HCB
    - Edmonds, Cecil Kay
    - Elizabethan Club, Yale University, 1913-58 (Box 1, Folder 64)
      Includes: Letters from Alfred Raymond Bellinger
      Includes: TLS from Andrew Keogh
      Includes: TLS from James Graham Leyburn
      Includes: ALS from Gilbert McCoy Troxell
      Includes: Two copies of letters, from [HCB to Alfred W. Pollard?] and from the Librarian of the Club to Pollard, concerning A Census of Shakespeare's Plays in Quarto
    - Esdaile, Arundell James Kennedy, 1923 Jun 9 (Box 1, Folder 65)
    - "F" General, 1923-45, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 66)
    - Fabyan, George, 1917 (Box 1, Folder 67)
      Includes: Two telegrams between George Fabyan and William Augustus White, and one copy of a letter from HCB to Fabyan
    - Ferris, Emery L., 1941-45 (Box 1, Folder 68)
    - Fisher, Otto Oren, 1946 Dec 13 (Box 1, Folder 69)
    - Fleming, John F., 1955 Mar 17 (Box 1, Folder 70)
      Includes: Notes on Shakespeare editions in HCB's hand, and a clipping about Fleming's purchase of the collection of A. S. W. Rosenbach
      See also: Rosenbach Company, Box 4, folder 214
    - Folger, Emily, 1922 Apr 26 (Box 1, Folder 71)
    - Folger, Henry Clay, 1920-29 (Box 1, Folder 72)
      Includes: TLS reply by HCB
    - Folger Shakespeare Library, 1933-46 (Box 1, Folder 73)
      Includes: Letters from James Gilmer McManaway
    - Forman, Maurice Buxton, 1933 (Box 1, Folder 74)
    - Förster, Max, 1923 Oct 19 (Box 2, Folder 75)
      Includes: Carbon of reply by HCB
    - Foyle, William Alfred, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 76)
    - Fox, Levi
      See: Trustees and Guardians of Shakespeare's Birthplace, Box 5, folder 246
    - Frost, H. Harvey, 1937 Apr 29 (Box 2, Folder 77)
    - Fulton, John Farquhar, 1935-56 (Box 2, Folder 78)
      Letter of 1956 is written at the end of a printed letter giving news of himself and of the Department of the History of Medicine at Yale
    - Ferguson, F. S. (Frederic Sutherland)
      See: Bernard Quaritch Ltd., Box 1, folder 19
    - Furness, Horace Howard, [n.y.] Dec-Feb (Box 2, Folder 79)
    - "G" General, 1921-34, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 80)
    - Gee, John Archer, 1934 Apr 30 (Box 2, Folder 81)
    - Gibson, Strickland, 1923 (Box 2, Folder 82)
    - Goff, Frederick Richmond
      See: Library of Congress, Rare Book Division, Box 3, folder 144
    - Granniss, Ruth S.
      See: Grolier Club, Box 2, folder 90
    - Greene, Belle da Costa
      See: Pierpont Morgan Library, Box 3, folder 189
    - Greenough, Chester Noyes, 1927 (Box 2, Folder 83)
    - Greg, Betty, 1940-41 (Box 2, Folder 84)
    - Greg, W. W. (Walter Wilson), 1920-50 (Box 2, Folder 85-88)
      Letter of June 14, 1920 removed from from Shakespeare's Merry Wives of Windsor, 1602, edited by W. W. Greg, [London] 1910
    - Griffith, Reginald Harvey, 1921-32 (Box 2, Folder 89)
    - Grolier Club, 1921-39 (Box 2, Folder 90)
      Includes: Copy of TL from HCB to the Club, n.d., and a typescript copy of her speech to the club, ca. 1935
      Includes: Letters from Ruth S. Granniss
      Includes: Letters from Lucius Wilmerding
    - Gunther, R. T. (Robert Theodore), 1920 Jul 21 (Box 2, Folder 91)
    - Guppy, Henry, 1923-41 (Box 2, Folder 92)
    - Hackett, Edmond Byrne
      See: Brick Row Book Shop, Box 1, folder 25
    - Hagen, Winston H., 1916 Mar 20 (Box 2, Folder 93)
    - Hake, Henry M., 1915-40 (Box 2, Folder 94)
      Includes: Part of a letter by HCB
    - Hannigan, John E., 1924-26, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 95)
    - Harbage, Alfred, 1955 (Box 2, Folder 96)
    - Harrison, G. B. (George Bagshawe), 1923-24 (Box 2, Folder 97)
      Includes: Copy of reply by HCB
    - Hebel, J. William, 1921-26 (Box 2, Folder 98)
    - Hemingway, Samuel Burdett, 1931 (Box 2, Folder 99)
    - Henry E. Huntington Library and Art Gallery, 1915-40 (Box 2, Folder 100-102)
      Includes: Letters from George Watson Cole, and copy of TL from HCB to Cole
      Includes: Letters from Cecil Kay Edmonds, and copy of TL from HCB to Edmonds
      Includes: TLS from Henry Edwards Huntington
    - Henry Sotheran Ltd., 1934 Jun 15 (Box 2, Folder 103)
    - Hickmott, Allerton C., 1948-59, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 104-105)
    - Hill, Reginald Harrison, 1931 (Box 2, Folder 106)
    - Hill, Walter M., 1937 (Box 2, Folder 107)
    - Hillebrand, Harold Newcomb, 1937-38 (Box 2, Folder 108)
    - Hillier, J. J., 1920 (Box 2, Folder 109)
      Includes: Copy of letter from HCB
      Includes: Specimen of Hillier's Shakespearian notes
    - Hogan, Frank J., 1934-44 (Box 2, Folder 110-111)
    - Holford, George Lindsay, 1920 Jun 7 (Box 2, Folder 112)
    - Holman, Louis A., 1932-33 (Box 2, Folder 113)
    - Holme, Strachan, 1914 (Box 2, Folder 114)
    - Hornby, Charles Harry St. John, 1929 (Box 2, Folder 115)
    - Horner, I. B. (Isaline Blew?), 1936 Jun 28 (Box 2, Folder 116)
    - Houghton, Arthur Amory, 1936 Nov 23 (Box 2, Folder 117)
    - Hunterian Museum, University of Glasglow, Library, 1914-46 (Box 2, Folder 118)
    - Huntington, Henry Edwards
    - Hyde, Mary Morley Crapo, 1941-48 (Box 2, Folder 119)
    - Maurice Inman, Inc., 1941 May 14 (Box 2, Folder 120)
    - Ivins, William Mills, 1927, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 121)
    - Jackson, William A., 1928-39 (Box 2, Folder 122)
      Includes: ALS from HCB
    - Jaggard, William, 1914 (Box 2, Folder 123)
    - James, M. R. (Montague Rhodes), 1923-34, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 124)
    - Japan Paper Company, 1927 Jan 17 (Box 3, Folder 125)
    - John Howell Books, 1955 Feb 24 (Box 3, Folder 126)
    - Johnson, John de Monins
      See: Oxford University Press, Box 3, folder 180
    - Jones, H. V., 1916-21 (Box 3, Folder 127)
      Includes: Copies of two letters by [HCB?] and one copy of a letter from Jones to the Yale University Press
    - Kane, Grenville, 1932 Feb 23 (Box 3, Folder 128)
    - Keogh, Andrew, 1916-34 (Box 3, Folder 129)
      Includes: Copy of a reply by HCB
      See also: Elizabethan Club, Box 1, folder 64
      See also: Yale University Library, Box 5, folder 273-278
    - Keynes, Geoffrey, 1916-54 (Box 3, Folder 130-133)
      Letter of March 1, 1920 includes letter by Margaret Darwin Keynes
    - Keynes, Margaret Darwin, 1917-41 (Box 3, Folder 134)
    - Knollenberg, Bernhard
    - "L" General, 1931-48 (Box 3, Folder 135)
    - Lane, William C., 1925 Dec 12 (Box 3, Folder 136)
    - Larsen, T., 1925-32 (Box 3, Folder 137)
    - Law, James D., 1922 Nov 11 (Box 3, Folder 138)
    - Lawrence, William W., 1935 Nov 25 (Box 3, Folder 139)
    - Leach, Howard Seavoy, 1930, 1946 (Box 3, Folder 140)
    - "Lord Leconfield" [H. A. Wyndham?], manuscript draft of a letter by HCB, 1926 (Box 3, Folder 141)
    - Lester, John A. Haverford College Library, 1951 (Box 3, Folder 142)
    - Lewis, Wilmarth Sheldon, 1929-42 (Box 3, Folder 143)
    - Library of Congress, Rare Book Division, 1948 Mar 15 (Box 3, Folder 144)
      Includes: Letters from Frederick Richmond Goff
    - Lister, P., 1925 (Box 3, Folder 145)
      "Hon. Sec. to the late A. H. Bullen"
    - Lowell, Amy, 1916 Jul 18 (Box 3, Folder 146)
    - McAlpin, Charles W., 1932 Nov 9 (Box 3, Folder 147)
    - MacDonald, Hugh, 1925 (Box 3, Folder 148)
    - McGill University Libraries, 1924, 1928 (Box 3, Folder 149)
    - Mackall, Leonard Leopold, 1926 Feb 20 (Box 3, Folder 150)
    - McKerrow, Ronald Brunlees, 1912-34 (Box 3, Folder 151)
      Includes: Carbon of a letter by [HCB?] and manuscript copy of a letter by HCB
    - McManaway, James Gilmer
      See: Folger Shakespeare Library, Box 1, folder 73
    - McMurtrie, Douglas C., 1926 Jan 21 (Box 3, Folder 152)
    - MacPherson, Harriet, 1931-35 (Box 3, Folder 153)
    - Madan, Falconer, 1921, 1934 (Box 3, Folder 154)
      Letter of July 29, 1934 removed from Madan's The Bodleian Library at Oxford, [London, 1919]
    - Manz, J. G., 1914 May 27 (Box 3, Folder 155)
    - Marlowe, Julia, 1919-27 (Box 3, Folder 156)
    - Marsh's Library, 1925-28 (Box 3, Folder 157)
      Includes: Letters from Newport B. White
    - Marx, Alexander, 1928 Apr 2 (Box 3, Folder 158)
    - Mason, William Smith, 1921 Jan 12 (Box 3, Folder 159)
    - Mersey, Charles Clive Bigham, 1937-46 (Box 3, Folder 160)
    - Meyer, H. H. B., 1928 Nov 22 (Box 3, Folder 161)
    - Meynell, Everard, [n.y.] Dec 3 (Box 3, Folder 162)
    - Millar, Eric George, 1922-44 (Box 3, Folder 163)
    - Miller, Richmond P., Jr., 1950 Feb 7 (Box 3, Folder 164)
    - Miner, Dorothy Eugenia
      See: Walters Art Gallery, Box 5, folder 256
    - Monrad, Anna Marie, 1942 Jun 1 (Box 3, Folder 165)
    - Morgan, J. P. (John Pierpont)
    - Morshead, Owen, 1948 (Box 3, Folder 166)
    - Moulton, Harold, 1941, 1946 (Box 3, Folder 167)
    - Murray, John, 1914-46 (Box 3, Folder 168)
    - National Library of Scotland, 1937-38 (Box 3, Folder 169)
    - National Library of Wales, 1948 (Box 3, Folder 170)
    - Neilson, William Allan, 1916 (Box 3, Folder 171)
    - New York Public Library, 1916, 1950 (Box 3, Folder 172)
    - Newton, Alfred Edward, 1919-27 (Box 3, Folder 173)
      Includes: Carbon of letter by HCB
    - Nicoll, Allardyce, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 174)
    - Odell, George Clinton Densmore, 1917, 1924 (Box 3, Folder 175)
    - Osborn, James Marshall, 1939-52 (Box 3, Folder 176)
    - Osborne, Lucy Eugenia, 1926 Sep 21 (Box 3, Folder 177)
    - Osgood, Charles Grosvenor, 1915-16 (Box 3, Folder 178)
    - Owen, John Isaac, 1941 May 30 (Box 3, Folder 179)
    - Oxford University Press, 1934-36 (Box 3, Folder 180)
      Includes: Letters from John de Monins Johnson
    - Papantonio, Michael, 1941-54 (Box 3, Folder 181)
    - Parke-Bernet Galleries, 1939-59 (Box 3, Folder 182)
    - Parrott, Thomas Marc, 1922-23 (Box 3, Folder 183)
    - Paul, Henry Neill, 1937-46 (Box 3, Folder 184)
      Includes: Carbon of letter from HCB dated February 12, 1937
    - Paul, ----, 1944 Sep 4 (Box 3, Folder 185)
    - Peabody Museum of Natural History, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 186)
      Acknowledgment note of gift
    - Pearson, Norman Holmes, 1955 Apr 8 (Box 3, Folder 187)
    - Peterson, Robert T., 1952 Jun 16 (Box 3, Folder 188)
    - Pforzheimer, Carl Howard
      See: Carl H. Pforzheimer Library, Box 1, folder 39
    - Pierpont Morgan Library, 1921-1948, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 189)
      Includes: Letters from Belle da Costa Greene, and carbon of TL from HCB to Greene
      Includes: TLS from J. P. Morgan
    - Plimpton, George A., 1915 Dec 8 (Box 3, Folder 190)
    - Pollard, Alfred W., 1911-37 (Box 4, Folder 191-202)
      Includes: Carbon of TLS to Pollard from the Cardiff, Wales Public Libraries dated May 4, 1916
      Includes: Two copies of unidentified typed letters to Pollard
    - Potter, Alfred Claghorn, 1929-32 (Box 4, Folder 203)
    - Pratt, Anne Stokely. ALS from HCB, 1946 Sep 24 (Box 4, Folder 204)
    - Pratt, Dallas, 1936 Feb 7 (Box 4, Folder 205)
    - Pratt Institute, Brooklyn. School of Library Science, 1925 Feb 28 (Box 4, Folder 206)
    - Princeton University Library, 1939 Oct 3 (Box 4, Folder 207)
      Acknowledgment letter for the receipt of A Census of Shakespeare's Plays in Quarto
    - "R" General, 1917-34 (Box 4, Folder 208)
    - Ricci, Seymour de, 1920-28 (Box 4, Folder 209)
    - Rickert, Edith, 1932 Jan 31 (Box 4, Folder 210)
    - Roberts, W., 1938 (Box 4, Folder 211)
    - Rollins, Carl Purington, 1940 May 18 (Box 4, Folder 212)
    - Rollins, Hyder Edward, 1927 (Box 4, Folder 213)
    - Rosenbach Company, 1935-46 (Box 4, Folder 214)
      Includes: Letters from A. S. W. Rosenbach
      Includes: TLS from John Fleming
    - Royal Shakespeare Theatre
      See: Shakespeare Memorial Theatre, Box 4, folder 226
    - "S" General, 1923-54 (Box 4, Folder 215)
    - St. John, Sheila, 1920 Feb 17 (Box 4, Folder 216)
      Includes: Sales catalog entitled "Collection of Wordsworthiana; Made by the late Mrs. Cynthia Morgan St. John of Ithaca, N.Y."
    - St. John's College, University of Cambridge, Library, 1920, 1921 (Box 4, Folder 217)
      Includes: Letters from William Henry Stevenson
    - Sanders, Cora Edgerton
      See: William Andrews Clark Memorial Library, Box 5, folder 263
    - Sargent, George Henry, 1920, 1922 (Box 4, Folder 218)
    - Sayle, Charles, 1921 Mar 31 (Box 4, Folder 219)
    - Scheide, John Hinsdale, 1931 Oct 3 (Box 4, Folder 220)
    - Schelling, Felix Emmanuel, 1916-32 (Box 4, Folder 221)
    - Scholfield, Alwyn Faber, 1921-46 (Box 4, Folder 222)
    - [Scott?], Biddy, 1940-41 (Box 4, Folder 223)
    - Scott, Douglas, 1940 (Box 4, Folder 224)
    - Shaaber, M. A., 1938-39 (Box 4, Folder 225)
    - Shakespeare Memorial Theatre, 1948 (Box 4, Folder 226)
    - Silver, Louis H., 1949 (Box 4, Folder 227)
    - Skinner, Otis, 1929 Feb 22 (Box 4, Folder 228)
    - Slater, Catherine P., 1915-25 (Box 4, Folder 229)
    - Smith, David Nichol, 1923 (Box 4, Folder 230)
    - Smith, Robert Metcalf, 1927-31 (Box 4, Folder 231)
    - Smith, Wilbur Moorehead, 1931, 1935 (Box 4, Folder 232)
    - Snyder, John T., 1930 Mar 25 (Box 4, Folder 233)
    - Sothern, E. H. (Edward Hugh), 1928 Dec 20 (Box 4, Folder 234)
      Includes: Christmas card from E. H. and Julia Marlowe Sothern
    - Sothern, Julia Marlowe
      See: Julia Marlowe, Box 3, folder 156
    - Spielmann, M. H. (Mabel Henrietta?), 1916 (Box 4, Folder 235)
    - Spurgeon, Caroline Frances Eleanor, 1930 Dec 2 (Box 4, Folder 236)
    - Stevenson, William Henry
      See: St. John's College, University of Cambridge, Library, Box 4, folder 217
    - Stillwell, Margaret Bingham, 1932 (Box 4, Folder 237)
    - Stuart, Michael Crichton, 1939-47 (Box 5, Folder 238)
    - Swann, Arthur
      See: Parke-Bernet Galleries, Box 3, folder 182
    - Tannenbaum, Samuel Aaron, 1924 Jul 17 (Box 5, Folder 239)
    - Texas Christian University, 1953-55 (Box 5, Folder 240)
    - Thompson, E. A., 1945 (Box 5, Folder 241)
    - Thompson, Lawrence Sidney
      See: University of Kentucky Libraries, Box 5, folder 251
    - Thorndike, Ashley Horace, 1917 Mar 20 (Box 5, Folder 242)
    - Tilley, Morris Palmer, 1926 (Box 5, Folder 243)
    - Tinker, Chauncey Brewster, 1931-50 (Box 5, Folder 244)
    - Trinity College, Dublin, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 245)